Finding aid to the Smith Club of Hartford records CA.MS.00091
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Hartford records
1896-2009
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Hartford
CA.MS.00091
2.083 linear feet (5 containers)
The Smith Club of Hartford was founded in 1896 as a means for former Smith College students, including non-graduates, to socialize. Its records contain minutes, membership directories, financial records, and correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series:
Series I: Membership and Minutes
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: Financial
Series IV: General Files-Program and Alphabetical
Biographical / Historical
The Smith Club of Hartford, Connecticut was founded in 1896 as a means for former Smith College students, including non-graduates, to socialize.
Related Materials
90.01 Alumnae Association records
Scope and Contents
The papers of the Smith Club of Hartford span a century from 1896 to 2003 with the bulk of the records being from the 1980s and 1990s. The earliest, handwritten registers of minutes and membership from 1896 to 1920 describe the social nature of the club which continues to be a main feature of the Club. The Club's records detail the events, lectures, and fundraisers held since its start in 1896, especially how central fundraising for the Alumnae Fund has been. The correspondence sheds light on problems of attracting and keeping members, hosting profitable fundraisers, and involving young alumnae. Changes and updates in the Club's events schedule show how the Club attempts to deal with these challenges and gives the researcher a sense of the changing sensibility from socializing to networking for the Club as it entered the twenty-first century.
Smith Club of Hartford; Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae.
- Series I: Minutes and Membership
  Scope and Contents
  This series covers the largest time-span of the Smith Club of Hartford records. The records begin with the founding of the club in 1896 through 1920. The minutes jump to the 1980s and continue through the late 1990s. The minutes by the Secretary cover Board meetings as well as General Body meetings and are fairly complete for the 1980s and 1990s. Copies of meeting announcements have been included with the minutes.
  The membership files contain membership directories, recruitment mailings to Hartford area alumae, and member participation questionnaires. Most material in the membership files is concentrated between 1989 and 1992.
  - Minutes and Membership, 1896-1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and Membership, 1902-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and Membership, 1910-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership handbooks, 1922, 1929,1958 (Box 1, Folder 3.1)
  - Minutes, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and Agendas, 1998-2002; undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Membership, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Membership, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Membership, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Membership, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Membership, 1998-2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Participation Questionnaire, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Participation Questionnaire and Results, 1991-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series II: Correspondence
  The correspondence includes invitations to non-Club events, information and newsletters from the Smith Alumnae Association, and letters between members regarding Club events. Like the membership files, the correspondence files from the 1989-1992 program years contain the most information.
  - Correspondence, 1929-1952 (Box 2, Folder 4.1)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 7.1)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondance, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series III: Financial
  The financial series includes Treasurer's records as well as information on the Club's fundraising events. Because fundraising for the Smith College Alumnae Fund is a high-priority for the Club, the Treasurer made periodic reports regarding the amount of the Club's bank account. The fundraising files include advertising and correspondence related to the Club's fundraising activities. Records about the Club's annual book sale and the beginning of its partnership with Hartford-based chef David Glass to sell chocolate mousse cakes are found in this series.
  - Correspondence, 1999-2009 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, No date (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Treasurer, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer, 1989-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising-Book Sale, 1978-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fundraising, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising, 1993-1996; undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising - Desserts by David Glass, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Series IV: General Files: Program and Alphabetical
  The general files include material that was mailed to Club members and mailings announcing individual events. The rest of the Club's records are arranged in the alphabetical files. These alphabetical files contain records of specific, non-annual events and miscellaneous notes.
  - Program, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Program, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Program, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Program, 1994-2003 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Program, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Three College Luncheon, 1988-2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - AARC Report, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Alumnae Admissions, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Alumnae Council, 1966; 1968; 1990-91 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Alum Status Change Reports, 1997-2002 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Annual Report, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Book Awards, 1990-2003 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Book Fund, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Book Group, 1989-2000 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Boston Smith Club, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Carol Christ Welcome, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1988-1998 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Club and Group Officer Handbook, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Community Involvement, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Constitution, 1977; 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Current Matters", 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Current Students List, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Event Reports, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - History of the Club (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Internships (SCIPI), 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ketcham Project, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Leadership Conference, 1996-2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Multi College Events, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Multi College Symposium, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - National Smith Club Information, 1992-2003 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Notes, MISC, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Notes, MISC, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Notes, MISC, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Notes, MISC, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Notes, MISC, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Richard H. Hersh, Trinity College Inauguration, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ruth Simmons Welcome, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Scholarships, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Silent Auction Conference, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Young Alums Events, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)